A Guide to the Stribling Family Papers, 1795-1993
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Stribling Family Papers, 1795-1993
The Library of Virginia
50403
11 reels of microfilm
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Lent for microfilming by William C. Stribling, Markham.
Biographical Information
Dr. Robert Mackay Stribling was born on 14 February 1793. He was the son of Thomas Stribling and Elizabeth Snickers. Dr. Stribling was a physician in Fauquier County, Virginia, where he lived on his estate "Mountain View." He married Caroline Matilda Clarkson (1800-1887) on 29 January 1818. Dr. Stribling died on 24 August 1862, and is buried in the Leeds Episcopal Church cemetery in Markham, Virginia.
His son, Robert Mackay Stribling, was born on 3 December 1833. He received training as a doctor and completed medical degrees at the University of Virginia and University of Pennsylvania in 1854, and 1856, respectively, practicing medicine briefly before the outbreak of the Civil War. He married 1) Mary Cary Ambler (1835-1868) and 2) Agnes Harwood Douthat (1849-1938). In June 1861, Stribling joined the Confederate Army and was made Captain of the Markham Guard and subsequently the Fauquier Artillery. Following the war, he returned to Markham and took over the family estate, "Mountain View." He was elected to the Virginia House of Delegates in 1879 and served until 1887. Stribling died on 27 March 1914, and is buried in the Leeds Episcopal Church cemetery in Markham, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1795-1993, of the Stribling family of Fauquier County, Virginia, including Dr. Robert Mackay Stribling (1793-1862) and his son Robert Mackay Stribling (1833-1914). The collection includes accounts and receipts, cash account ledgers, correspondence, daybooks, deeds, estate papers, historical information on the Fauquier Artillery (Stribling's Battery), ledgers, lecture notes, lists of balances due, medical accounts, report cards, and tax records.
There is a considerable amount of material relating to the management of the family estate "Mountain View," including deeds and surveys, bills for building materials, and farm ledgers. The collection also includes an orderly book, 1814-1815, of Lt. Turner Ashby (1789-1835).
Contents List
- Abbott, Ezra. (Reel 6105)
- Account Book, 1814-1816. (Reel 6105)
- Account Ledger 1855-1870. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1810-1819. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1820-1829. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1830-1833. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1834-1836. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1837-1839. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1840-1849. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1850-1859. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1860-1879. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1882, undated. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts - Not Sorted. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts and Receipts - Clarkson, William. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts - Harriet (Servant). (Reel 6105)
- Accounts Not Settled, 1849. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts, Notes, Claims, etc., 1812-1819. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts, Notes, Claims, etc., 1820-1829. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts, Notes, Claims, etc., 1830-1839. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts, Notes, Claims, etc., 1840-1849. (Reel 6105)
- Accounts, Notes, Claims, etc., 1850-1859. (Reel 6105)
- The Acorn - Markham Graded School, 1922-1923. (Reel 6106)
- Adams, James W. and W. George. (Reel 6106)
- Address - Winchester, VA, 6 June 189?. (Reel 6106)
- Alexandria Gazette. (Reel 6106)
- Ambler, John. (Reel 6106)
- Ash, William and Harriet. (Reel 6106)
- Ashby, Albert A.. (Reel 6106)
- Ashby & Herbert. (Reel 6106)
- Ashby & Marshall. (Reel 6106)
- Ashby, Somerville & Co.. (Reel 6106)
- Ashby & Wood. (Reel 6106)
- Ayre, George L.. (Reel 6106)
- Barbie, Turner D.. (Reel 6106)
- Bastable & Hunton. (Reel 6106)
- Bell, Robert. (Reel 6106)
- Benedict, Lewis. (Reel 6106)
- Bills for Building Materials. (Reel 6106)
- Bills for Building Materials - Hartland. (Reel 6106)
- Bills for Building Materials - Mountain View. (Reel 6106)
- Bolen, A.R.. (Reel 6106)
- Bolen & Templeman. (Reel 6106)
- Bradford, B.T.. (Reel 6106)
- Bradley, C.C.. (Reel 6106)
- Cash Account Ledger, 1817-1822. (Reel 6107)
- Cash Account Ledger, 1822-1829. (Reel 6107)
- Cattle Sales, 1851. (Reel 6107)
- Cawood, Daniel. (Reel 6107)
- Chancellor, John J.. (Reel 6107)
- Class Notebook - Henry C. Stribling, 1858. (Reel 6107)
- Correspondence, 1812-1857. (Reel 6107)
- Correspondence, 1861-1926. (Reel 6110)
- Correspondence - Samuel Dyson to William Clarkson, 1813-1816. (Reel 6110)
- Correspondence - John Riley Lease. (Reel 6110)
- Correspondence - Dr. T.W. Smith, 1822-1846. (Reel 6110)
- Correspondence - Thomas Stribling to Dr. Robert M. Stribling, 1841. (Reel 6110)
- Correspondence - Medical, 1815-1860. (Reel 6110)
- Correspondence - Miscellaneous. (Reel 6110)
- "Crawley" Division Surveys. (Reel 6110)
- Cross, R.Y.. (Reel 6110)
- Currency. (Reel 6110)
- Daybook - Medical Visits, 18 September 1822 - 17 January 1824. (Reel 6110)
- Daybook - Robert M. Stribling & Son, 16 October 1855 - 1 August 1859. (Reel 6110)
- Deeds, 1834-1894. (Reel 6110)
- Deeds - Abbott, Ezra - Lot and Bradford. (Reel 6110)
- Deeds - "Canaan" Farm - Little to Stribling, 1886. (Reel 6110)
- Deeds - Douthat, Robert. (Reel 6110)
- Deeds - (West) Virginia, 1840-1841. (Reel 6110)
- Essex, William. (Reel 6109)
- Estate of Thomas Ambler. (Reel 6109)
- Estate of William Clarkson, 1811-1817. (Reel 6109)
- Estate of William Clarkson, 1817-1818. (Reel 6109)
- Estate of William Clarkson, 1818-1822. (Reel 6109)
- Estate of William Clarkson - Not Sorted. (Reel 6109)
- Estate of Caroline Clarkson Stribling. (Reel 6109)
- Estate of Dr. Robert M. Stribling. (Reel 6109)
- Farm Accounts Ledger, 1942-1957. (Reel 6109)
- Farm Ledger - Clermont, 1823. (Reel 6109)
- Farmers Bank of Virginia. (Reel 6109)
- Fauquier Artillery. (Reel 6108)
- The Fauquier Artillery at Gettysburg. (Reel 6108)
- Foster & Co.. (Reel 6108)
- Grayson, J.W.. (Reel 6108)
- Green, A.G.. (Reel 6108)
- Green, William. (Reel 6108)
- "Hartland" and Adjoining Tracts - Deeds and Surveys, 1818-1822. (Reel 6108)
- "Hartland" and Adjoining Tracts - Deeds and Surveys, 1831-1841. (Reel 6108)
- "Hartland" and Adjoining Tracts - Deeds and Surveys, 1843-1860. (Reel 6108)
- Hume, Marshall & Ward. (Reel 6108)
- Hume, W.M.. (Reel 6108)
- Humphreys & Taliaferro. (Reel 6108)
- Insurance Papers, 1880-1899. (Reel 6111)
- Isham Keith & Co.. (Reel 6111)
- Jett & Green. (Reel 6111)
- Keith & Chilton. (Reel 6111)
- Kerrick Family. (Reel 6111)
- Latin Notebook - Thomas M. Ambler, 1846. (Reel 6111)
- Ledger, 1795-1818. (Reel 6111)
- Ledger, 1859-1870. (Reel 6111)
- Ledger, 1865-1881. (Reel 6111)
- Ledger - Mountain View Farm, 1820-1826. (Reel 6111)
- Ledger - Mountain View Farm, 1826-1832. (Reel 6112)
- Ledger - Mountain View Farm, 1832-1845. (Reel 6112)
- Ledger - Dr. William C. Stribling, 1841-1866. (Reel 6112)
- Leeds Farm Division. (Reel 6112)
- Legislative Records, Speeches, Notes, etc.. (Reel 6112)
- Legislative Records, Speeches, Notes, etc. (continued). (Reel 6113)
- Letterbook - Clara Lee to Emma Painly. (Reel 6113)
- Licences to Practice Medicine. (Reel 6113)
- Lists of Accounts for Collection, 1823. (Reel 6113)
- Lists of Balances Due, 1816. (Reel 6113)
- Lists of Balances Due, 1819-1823. (Reel 6113)
- Lists of Balances Due, 1820. (Reel 6113)
- Lists of Balances Due, 1820-1822. (Reel 6113)
- Lists of Balances Due, 1827-1829. (Reel 6113)
- Lists of Balances Due, 1829. (Reel 6113)
- Lists of Balances Due, 1836. (Reel 6113)
- Markham Packing House Co.. (Reel 6113)
- Markham Post Office. (Reel 6113)
- Markham Station Receipts. (Reel 6113)
- Marshall & Co.. (Reel 6113)
- Marshall & Ward. (Reel 6113)
- Marshall, James K., Jr.. (Reel 6113)
- Marshall, John - Land Divisions. (Reel 6113)
- Marshall, William - Moss Hollow Tract. (Reel 6113)
- McKay Family - Income and Expense Ledger, 1917-1943. (Reel 6113)
- Medical Account Book - Dr. William C. Stribling, 1841-1842. (Reel 6113)
- Medical Account Book, 1855-1856. (Reel 6113)
- Medical Accounts, 1815-1854. (Reel 6113)
- Medical Accounts, 1820-1824. (Reel 6113)
- Medical Lecture Notes 1810-1811. (Reel 6113)
- Medical Lecture Notes 1811-1812. (Reel 6114)
- Medical Lecture Notes and Daybook, 1812-1813. (Reel 6114)
- Medical Lecture Notes, undated. (Reel 6114)
- Medical - Miscellaneous. (Reel 6114)
- Medical Notebook. (Reel 6114)
- Memorandum Book, 1807-1811. (Reel 6114)
- Memorandum Book, 1814-1818. (Reel 6114)
- Militia Appointment, 1814. (Reel 6114)
- Robert H. Miller, Son & Co.. (Reel 6114)
- Miscellaneous Notebook. (Reel 6114)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1808-1829. (Reel 6114)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1830-1838. (Reel 6114)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1840-1859. (Reel 6114)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1860-1877. (Reel 6114)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1880-1887. (Reel 6114)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1888-1905, undated. (Reel 6114)
- Moncure, George V.. (Reel 6114)
- Moore & Waller. (Reel 6114)
- Mountain View Farm - Miscellaneous. (Reel 6114)
- Nursing School Notes, 1909. (Reel 6115)
- Orderly Book of Lt. Turner Ashby, 1814-1815. (Reel 6115)
- Payne, Mason B. & Arthur M.. (Reel 6115)
- Petty, John B.. (Reel 6115)
- Phillips, Thomas. (Reel 6115)
- Photographs (copies). (Reel 6115)
- Poetry. (Reel 6115)
- Post Offices. (Reel 6115)
- William L. Powell & Son. (Reel 6115)
- Priestly. (Reel 6115)
- Program - John Marshall 100th Anniversary Banquet, 4 February 1901. (Reel 6115)
- Recipes. (Reel 6115)
- Record Book (Unidentified). (Reel 6115)
- Reid, John and Mark. (Reel 6115)
- Royston, Joseph A.. (Reel 6115)
- Runaway Slaves Advertisement (copy). (Reel 6115)
- School Reports - Henry C. Stribling, 1852-1856. (Reel 6115)
- School Reports - Robert M. Stribling, 1853. (Reel 6115)
- School Reports - Thomas E. Stribling, 1841. (Reel 6115)
- Slaves. (Reel 6115)
- Speech - Henry St. George Tucker, 30 July 1896. (Reel 6115)
- William Stabler & Bro.. (Reel 6115)
- Stewart, J.M.. (Reel 6115)
- Stone Church. (Reel 6115)
- Stribling & Ashby. (Reel 6115)
- Stribling, Henry C. - Upperville Academy and UVA. (Reel 6115)
- Surveys - Index. (Reel 6115)
- Tax Bills, 1813-1861. (Reel 6115)
- Taxes. (Reel 6115)
- Templeman, G.B. (Building Materials). (Reel 6115)
- A Treatise on Sulphurous Waters by John Armstrong, M.D., 1826. (Reel 6115)
- Tuition and Expenses, 1840-1842. (Reel 6115)
- Vaughn, Gary. (Reel 6115)
- The V.M.I. and Her Past by Joseph R. Anderson, 1904. (Reel 6115)
- White, Charles H.. (Reel 6115)
- White & Smith. (Reel 6115)
- Will of Martin Pickett, 1803. (Reel 6115)
- Will of Agnes H. Stribling, 1936. (Reel 6115)
- Will of Dr. Robert M. Stribling. (Reel 6115)
- Will of Robert M. Stribling, ca. 1901. (Reel 6115)